Andrew Hawileh

Plano, TX | 469-744-1118 | andrewh829@gmail.com | http://andrewhawileh.com/

| LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium Blog |

Full Stack Software Developer

Experienced in Flask, Node and JavaScript based programming with a background in Java. I possess strong team building and critical thinking skills that help well structured companies achieve their goals, benefit the synergy of our team, and meet deadlines. I always find myself targeting leader oriented roles and I always strive to excel in my interests, as well as my career.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript (ES6), Express/Node, Prisma, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

BOSS (Best One Stop Shop) - Github | Demo

- Utilized a mock Rest API (using json-server) to mimic an online storefront for purchasing cars...
- A user can purchase a car and list their own car for sale, all changes persisted using a json file as a database.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Find That Recipe - Github | Demo

- Uses a mock Rest API in unison with a free public API, themealdb.com
- Allows the user to search through food recipes, filtered by a category, add recipes to a list of favorites, and publish their own recipe.
- React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Finance Tracker - Github | Demo

- Uses Python and SQLAlchemy to save users information
- A user can interact with the CLI to add or remove expenses, view their monthly savings, see a proper budget, and save their list of monthly expenditures to a PDF file.
- Python, SQLite, SQLAlchemy

EXPERIENCE

AAMZ Services Allen, TX

UPS Store Associate

07/2022 - 02/2023

- Assisted customers with shipping and packing, Notaries, and Insurance claims, as well as corporate returns to companies such as Spectrum, ATT, Apple, etc.
- Handled packages and mail for +-200 mailbox customers
- On some occasion, prepare the store to be opened at no later than 8:30AM

Marcus Fish Tanks Plano, TX

Contractor

07/2020 - 04/2021

- Mixed a collection of 5 chemicals to make an aguarium plant fertilizer to be shipped and sold online.
- Assisted with the photo collection of various plants to be used as thumbnails on the storefront.
- Assisted in physical labor to move office buildings, unload shipments from pallets, and reformat the layout of the warehouse.

EDUCATION

Self Taught

Node/Express, Prisma

Flatiron School

Online (Live)

Full Stack Web Development, JavaScript (ES6), React, Python, Flask

02/2023-06/2023

Collin CollegeAssociate of Science Degree. (Computer Science Focus)

Plano, TX

12/2022